Guide to the Charles Wilkes Papers, 1816-1876 RL.01383
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Maryland. Annapolis. Schools and Academies. United States Naval Academy 1826 Jan. 26; 1847 Mar. 10; 1847 Apr. 12; 1847 Apr. 26; 1847 May 23; 1847 June 6; 1847 June 20; 1847 July 7; 1847 Dec. 11; 1848 Jan. 27; 1849 Oct. 10; 1857 June 8; 1860 May 28.
Maryland. Baltimore. Civil War, 1863 Apr. 1
Maryland. Baltimore. Description and Travel 1853 Jan. 10; Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, pp. 264-266.
Maryland. Baltimore. Parks. Howard Park Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, pp. 265-266
Maryland. Baltimore. Railroads, Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, p.264
Maryland. Baltimore. Schools and Academies. Peabody Institute Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, p. 266
Maryland. Port Deposit. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV)
Mason, John Young 1848 Jan. 27; 1849 Aug. 25.
Mason, Richard Barnes Letter to: 1836 May 27; Letter to: 1836 July 2; Letter to: 1840 Mar. 30; 1835 July; 1836 Jan.-June; 1836 July 25; 1836 Aug. 30; 1837 Feb. 22; 1837 Feb. 27; 1837 Mar. 11; 1837 Mar. 13; 1837 Mar. 24; 1838 May 17; 1840 Mar.-Nov. (scattered); 1842 Feb. 20; 18
Massachusetts. Banks and Banking 1850 Apr. 19
Massachusetts. Boston. Boston City Library 1855, Dec. 17
Massachusetts. Boston. Churches, 1850 Jan. 14
Massachusetts. Boston. Social Life and Customs 1850 Jan. 1; 1850 Jan. 11.
Massachusetts. Boston. Fire Alarms, 1852 Nov. [?]; 1852 Dec. 3.
Massachusetts. Cambridge. Schools and Academies. Lawrence Scientific School 1849 Sept. 6; 1850 Aug. 7; 1850 Sept. 9; 1850 Oct. 11; 1850 Nov. 7; 1851 Jan. 2.
Massachusetts. Sleighing 1850 Jan. 3
Mauna Loa. Discovery and Exploration, 1840 Dec. 11; 1840 Dec. 31; 1841 Jan. 24.
Maury, Matthew Fontaine 1851 May 14; 1851 July 20; 1851; 1853 June 1; 1856 Jan. 19; 1856 Jan. 29; 1862 Nov. 25[?].
Maxwell, Hugh 1842 July 15
Maynadier, William 1871 May 12
Mecklenburg Copper Mining Company, 1853 May 31; 1856 Mar. 7; 1856 Mar. 31.
Mecklenburg Declaration of Independence, 1857 May 17; 1857 May 24; 1875 May 16; 1875 May 19.
Mecklenburg Gold Mining Company, 1868 Jan. 17
Mecklenburg Iron Works 1867 Mar. 28; 1868 Feb. 3; 1868 Feb. 26; 1870 May 23; 1870 May 26; 1870 Oct. 10; 1871 Jan. 1; 1871 Feb. 15; 1871 Feb. 22; 18
Medicine. Home Remedies 1854 June 16
Meehan, John Silva 1849 June 15; 1849 June 22; 1857 Dec. 24.
Meigs, Montgomery Cunningham, 1862 Oct. 7; 1862 Dec. 3; 1862 Dec. 4.
Merchant Seamen. Missions and Charities. China 1850 June 23
Merchants. China 1850 Dec. 3; 1850 Dec. 29.
Merchant Ships 1850 Dec. 3; 1851 Dec. 8.
Meredith William Morris Letter to: 1850 May 24 (enclosed with letter of 1850 May 25); 1849 Mar. 10.
Metcalfe, Thomas 1827[?] Mar. 7
Meteorology 1851 Apr. 19; 1856 Feb. 8; 1856 Feb. 15.
Meteorology. Observations 1850 Mar. 7; 1856 Feb. 18.
Mexican War 1847 Dec. 27; 1848 Jan. 23.
Mexico. Coastal Surveys 1848 Jan. 19; 1848 Feb. 4.
Mexico. Food. Prices 1848 Feb. 27
Mexico. Foreign Relations. United States 1846 Apr. 3
Mexico. Hotels. Bell's Hotel, 1848 Feb. 27
Mexico. Laguna de Terminos. Description and Travel 1848 Jan. 19
Mexico. Tuspan Reef. Description and Travel 1848 Mar. 17
Mexico. Vera Cruz. Description and Travel 1847 Dec. 6; 1848 Jan. 5; 1848 Feb. 24.
Michigan. Description and Travel, 1836 June 19
Michigan. Immigration 1836 June 19
Michigan. Land. Sales and Transfers, 1836 June 19
Migration. Internal. Western States, 1836 June 19; 1857 Nov. 29.
Mill Wheels 1853 Nov. 14
Miller, William Starr Legal Papers: 1848 ca. May 9; Legal Papers: 1850 May 7.
Mills and Millwork 1849 June 7
Mills and Millwork. North Carolina 1848 Aug. 29; 1848 Oct. 26; 1848 Nov. 3; 1848 Nov. 8; 1848 Nov. 19; 1848 Nov. 22; 1848 Nov. 23; 1848 Nov. 24; 1848 Nov. 30; 1848 Dec. 7; 1848 Dec. 9; 1848 Dec. 10; 1848 Dec. 27; 1849 Jan.-Apr. (scattered); 1865 May 28; 1866 July 9.
Mills and Millwork. North Carolina. Charlotte 1854 Jan. 10
Mills and Millwork. North Carolina. McGinn, 1855 June 10; 1855 July 21; 1855 Aug. 1.
Mills and Millwork. North Carolina. St. Catherine's Mills 1848 Nov.-1851 Oct. (scattered); 1852 Oct. 7; 1853 Mar.-1853 Sept. (scattered); 1860 July 18; 1866 Nov. 9; 1870 Feb. 13; 1870 Apr. 11; 1870 Apr. 20; 1871 May 24.
Mills, Clark 1850 Aug. 21
Mills, Robert (1781-1855) 1849 July [?]
Millstones 1849 Sept. 20; 1849 Nov. 21; 1849 Nov. 22; 1849 Dec. 24; 1849 Dec. 29.
Mines and Mining. North Carolina 1859; 1867 Mar. 28; 1872 June 17; 1874 Mar. 29.
Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Claremont Mine 1856 Feb. 4
Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Conrad Hill Mine 1853 Oct. 30
Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Harlan Mine 1853 Oct. 30
Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Long Creek Mine 1876 Apr. 16; 1876.
Mines and Mining. Virginia 1853 Oct. 23
Mining Machinery 1848 Dec. 26; 1848 Dec. 27; 1848 Dec. 31; 1849 Jan. 17; 1853 June 25; 1853 June 27 (2); 1853 June 29; 1853 July 12; 1853 July 13; 1853 July 16; 1853 July 19; 1853 Oct. 23; 1853 Oct. 25; 1853 Nov. 1; 1853 Dec. 8; 1853 Dec. 14; 1854 Apr. 19 (enclosed with l
Minnesota. Agriculture Writings: Trip to the Far West
Minnesota. Depressions. 1857, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter V)
Minnesota. Description and Travel, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VIII)
Minnesota. Fort Snelling Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VI)
Minnesota. Hastings. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapters V and X)
Minnesota. Indians Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VI)
Minnesota. Lake Calhoun Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VIII)
Minnesota. Lake Como Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter V)
Minnesota. Lake Harriet Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VIII)
Minnesota. Lake Minnetonka Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VIII)
Minnesota. Minneapolis. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VI)
Minnesota. Minnehaha Creek and Falls, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VI)
Minnesota. Redwing. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter IX)
Minnesota. St. Anthony Falls, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VI)
Minnesota. St. Paul. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapters V, VII, VIII, IX)
Minnesota. White Bear Lake Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VII)
Minnesota. Winona. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter IX)
Mississippi River. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapters IV, V, IX, X)
Missouri. St. Louis. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XI)
Missouri Compromise 1850 June 19
Mitchel, Ormsby MacKnight Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XII, p. 129)
Mollusks 1850 Nov. 29; 1851 Oct. 20.
Monkeys 1831 Apr. 26
Monroe, Elizabeth (Kortright), 1825 Mar. 22
Montgomery, John Berrien [?], 1850 Mar. 4; 1863 Apr. 14.
Morehead, John Motley 1853 Oct. 30; 1858 Feb. 7.
Morell, George Webb 1863 Jan. 4; 1863 Apr. 19; 1863 Apr. 23; 1863 May 29 (part of letter of May 28).
Morrill, Lot Myrick Letter to: 1873 Jan. 30; 1874 May 28.
Morris, Charles (1784-1856), 1827 Mar. 9[?]; 1827 Mar. 12.
Morris, Charles (1784-1856) [?], 1846 Feb. 17; 1854 Nov. 10.
Murat, Achille Napoléon 1827 Mar. 8[?]
Mules 1849 Sept. 20
Murchison, Sir Roderick Impey, First Baronet 1851 June 11
Murder. Fiji Islands 1849 Aug. 10; Volume: 1840 July 15.
Muscadine Grapes 1859 Nov. 23; 1860 Feb. 8.
Muskingum River 1852 Aug. 26
Mustache 1838 Sept. 26; 1838 Oct. 21.
Nash, Frederick 1857 May 24
Native Races. Carlshoff 1839 Sept. 12
Native Races. Clermont-Tonnerre 1839 Sept. 12
Native Races. Disappointment Islands, 1839 Sept. 12
Native Races. Fiji Islands 1840 Aug. 10; 1840 Aug. 18.
Native Races. Islands of the Pacific, 1839 Sept. 12
Native Races. Matia 1839 Sept. 12
Native Races. New Zealand 1839 Nov. 3; 1840[?] Mar..
Native Races. Raraka 1839 Sept. 12
Native Races. Society Islands 1839 Sept. 12
Native Races. South Sea Islands 1836 Nov. 3
Native Races. Sulu Island [?] 1839 Sept. 12
Native Races. Terra del Fuego 1839 Mar. 31
Natural History 1850 Apr. 10
Nautical Instruments 1833 [?]; 1836 July 18; 1836 Sept. 7; 1836 Oct. 9; 1836 Oct. 12; 1836 Nov. 3; 1837 Jan. 30 (2); 1837 Sept. 2; 1837 Nov. 17 (enclosed with letter of Nov. 30); 1837 Dec. 7; 1838 Jan. 8; 1838 Apr. 4; 1838 Apr. 7; 1838 June 4.
Navigation. Mathematics 1843 Nov. 7
Negro Blacksmiths. North Carolina 1849 Aug. 18
Negro Criminals 1849 May 17
Negro Debtor and Creditor 1867 Mar. 14
Negro Laborers 1856 Jan. 29; 1856 May 31; 1856 Oct. 12; 1865 June 20.
Negro Millers 1856 Nov. 18
Negro Miners. North Carolina 1854[?] Jan. 1; 1857 Nov. 29; 1876 Apr. [?].
Negro Railroad Construction Workers, 1865 May 28
Negro Servants 1830 Sept. 2 [?]
Negroes 1834 July 16; 1837 Dec. 25.
Negroes. North Carolina 1875 Aug. 29; 1876 Jan. 8.
New England Glass Company Works, 1850 Oct. 29
New Hampshire. Portsmouth 1862 Nov. 4
New Jersey. Belleville. Description and Travel Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, pp. 254-259
New Jersey. Iron Industry and Trade, 1836 Aug. 6
New Jersey. Jersey City. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XVI)
New Jersey. Llewellyn Park. Description and Travel Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, pp. 253-254
New Jersey. Newark. Description and Travel Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, pp. 260-261
New Jersey. Newark. Railroads Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVIII, p.264
New Jersey. Patterson. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV)
Railroads. New Jersey 1849 Sept. 7
New Jerusalem Church 1825 Aug. 9
New York. Amsterdam [?]. Houses, 1825[?] June 1
New York. Batavia. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV)
New York. Buffalo. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIV)
New York. Description and Travel, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV)
New York. Devasego. Description and Travel 1853 Sept. 2; 1853 Sept. 6.
New York. Diseases. Cholera, 1849 June 7
New York. Dunkirk. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIV)
New York. Elections 1834 Apr. 12
New York. Elmira. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV)
New York. Fourth of July Celebrations, 1830 July
New York. Geological Surveys, 1844 May 5
New York. Naval Yards and Naval Stations 1844 Feb. 9
New York. New York. Catholic Church, Writings: "Churches" p. 2
New York. New York. Cemeteries. Greenwood Cemetery Writings: "Greenwood Cemetery"
New York. New York. Charities, Writings: "Churches" p. 2
New York. New York. Churches, Writings: "Churches"
New York. New York. Commerce, Writings: "Commerce of New York"
New York. New York. Description and Travel Writings: About New York; Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XVI).
New York. New York. Dry Docks, 1835 Mar. 18
New York. New York. Fire Departments, Writings: "Fire Department"
New York. New York. Hotels Writings: "Hotels"
New York. New York. Hotels. French's Hotel 1860 Oct. 3
New York. New York. Houses Untitled, pp. 10-12
New York. New York. Opera Writings: "Theatres," pp. 1-2
New York. New York. Parks. Central Park Writings: Fire Department, pp. 7 and following; Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XVI).
New York. New York. Politics and Government Writings: "Courts and Administration"
New York. New York. Population, Writings: "Population of New York"
New York. New York. Protestant Episcopal Church. Trinity Episcopal Church Legal Papers: 1862 Mar. 25; Writings: "Churches," p. 1 (2 sides).
New York. New York. Railroads, Writings: "Railways"
New York. New York. Restaurants, Lunch Rooms, Etc. Writings: "Hotels," pp. 3-4
New York. New York. Social Life and Customs Writings: "Fire Department," pp. 3-7
New York. New York. Theater, Writings: "Theaters"
New York. New York. Universities and Colleges. Columbia College [?] 1849 May 8
New York. New York. Universities and Colleges. Columbia University Writings: Untitled, pp. 6-9
New York. New York. Wall Street, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XVI)
New York. New York. Water Supply, Writings: Crotan Water Works"
New York. Niagra Falls Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapters XIV and XV)
New York. Niagra Falls. Description and Travel 1852 Aug. 31
New York. Political Parties. Democratic Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV, pp. 153-154)
New York. Resorts 1848 June 16
New York. Riots 1834 July 16; 1849 May 14.
New York. Servants 1830 Sept. 2[?]
New York. Shipwrecks 1837 Jan. 7
New York. Social Life and Customs, 1825 Aug. 5
New York. Stagecoach Travel, 1834 Oct. 13
New York. Staten Island. Description and Travel Writings: Untitled, Chapter XVII, pp. 249-250
New York. Sunday Schools 1854 Sept. 13
New York. Theaters. Opera Houses, 1849 May 16
New York. Tioga County. Maps, 1829 Nov. 30
New York. United States. Mint, 1846 Jan. 20; 1846 Jan. 25; 1846 Feb. 3.
Weddings. New York 1830 Nov. 11
New York Central Railroad Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIV)
Nicaragua. Greytown 1859 Oct. 21
Nicholson, James William Augustus, 1863 Jan. 4; 1863 Feb. 4; 1863 Feb. 11; 1863 Feb. 24; 1863 Mar. 10; 1863 Mar. 18; 1863 Apr. 4; 1863 Apr. 8; 1863 May 19.
Nicholson, John B. [?] 1838 Nov. 25; 1838 Dec. 18; 1838 Dec. 22; 1839 Jan. 5.
North, William 1826 Nov. 18
North Carolina. Agriculture, 1856 May 31
North Carolina. Alcoholism and Crime, 1874 July 27
North Carolina. Banks and Banking, 1870 Aug. 3
North Carolina. Building Stones, Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina, p. 11)
North Carolina. Charlotte. Banks and Banking 1865 May 20; 1865 June 20; 1866 Dec. 14.
North Carolina. Charlotte. Commerce, 1857 Apr. 12
North Carolina. Charlotte. Copper Mines and Mining 1853 Sept. 2
North Carolina. Charlotte. Description and Travel 1853 Apr. 5; 1853 Apr. 9; 1855 Dec. 2.
North Carolina. Charlotte. Fires, 1871 Nov. 17
North Carolina. Charlotte. Gold Mines and Mining 1849 Jan. 3; 1849 Jan. 3.
North Carolina. Charlotte. Mills and Millwork 1854 Jan. 10
North Carolina. Charlotte. Population, 1850 Oct. 24 (attached to letter of Oct. 2)
North Carolina. Charlotte. Protestant Episcopal Church. St. Peter's Episcopal Church 1875 Feb. 7; 1875 Mar. 14.
North Carolina. Charlotte [?]. Schools and Academies. North Carolina Military Institute, 1872 Jan. 10
North Carolina. Chatham County. Gold Mines and Mining 1871 Nov. 1
North Carolina. Clay Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," p. 11)
North Carolina. Clergy 1866 June 21
North Carolina. Commerce 1857 Nov. 29
North Carolina. Copper Mines and Mining. Hipps[?] Mine 1849 Feb. 3; 1849 Feb. 13; 1849 Feb. 18; 1849 Feb. 28.
North Carolina. Cotton Trade, 1865 June 20; 1866 Dec. 6; 1866 Dec. 14.
North Carolina. Currency 1865 May 20; 1865 May 28.
North Carolina. Description and Travel, 1848 Apr. 18
North Carolina. Diseases. Cholera, 1849 May 8
North Carolina. Diseases. Measles, 1857 Mar. 15
North Carolina. Diseases. Smallpox, 1851 Jan. 21
North Carolina. Economic Conditions, 1865 June 20; 1866 June 5; 1866 July 9; 1866 July 11; 1866 July 30; 1866 Dec. 6; 1866 Dec. 14; 1868 Feb. 3.
North Carolina. Elections 1848 Nov. 9; 1860 Nov. 8; 1860 Nov. 23; 1874 Aug. 10.
North Carolina. Flour. Manufacture and Trade 1857 July 5; 1858 May 9; 1858 June 24; 1858 June 25.
North Carolina. Flour Mills 1850 Apr. 13; 1856 Aug. 26; 1857 Feb.-June (scattered); 1857 July 12; 1857 Aug. 2; 1858 Aug. 8-1859 Sept. 11 (scattered); 1859 Sept. 11.
North Carolina. Gaston. Civil War, 1866 Mar. 28
North Carolina. General Assembly, 1861 Feb. 6
North Carolina. Geology Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 3-14
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining, 1848 Aug.-1849 Apr. (letters of Charles and Edmund Wilkes); 1853 Apr. 5; 1876 Apr. 8; 1876 Apr. 16.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Alexander Mine 1853 Apr. 19
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Asbury Mine Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 9-10,15)
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Brush(y) Hill Mine 1849 Mar. 22; 1854 July 16; 1854 Aug. 20; 1858 Mar. 31.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Caldwell Mine 1849 Nov. 26
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Capp's Gold Mine 1848 Aug-1849 June (scattered, especially see letters of Edmund Wilkes); 1849 Nov.-1850 Dec. (scattered, especially see letters of Edmund Wilkes); 1851 Jan. 1; 1851 Jan. 2; 1851 Mar. 10; 1851 Mar. 19; 1851 June 23; 1851 July 12; 1851 Aug. 3; 1851 Aug. 6
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Charlotte Hill Mine 1848 Dec. 9; 1848 Dec. 17; 1848 Dec. 27; 1849 Jan. 4; 1849 Jan. 10; 1849 Jan. 21; 1849 Feb. 10; 1849 Mar. 17; 1849 Mar. 21; 1849 Mar. 22; 1849 Mar. 25; 1849 Mar. 29 (2); 1849 Apr. 4; 1849 Apr. 14; 1849 Apr. 20; 1849 Apr. 23; 1849 Apr. 30; 1849 May 6; 1849
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Davidson Gold Mine 1848 Dec. 31; 1849 Jan. 20.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Duffie Mine 1853 Apr. 22
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Dunn's [?] Gold Mine 1848 Dec. 31; 1849 Jan. 16; 1853 Apr. 16.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Felt Mine 1849 Feb. 10; 1853 Aug. 21.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Gold Hill Mine 1856 Mar. 16; 1874 Mar. 29; 1874 June 5.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. High Shoals Mine Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 9-10)
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Howie Mine 1854 Jan. 28; 1854 July 23; 1854 Aug. 13 (with letter of July 30); 1855 Mar. 4; 1855 Mar. 18; 1855 Apr. 8; 1855 Apr. 17; 1855 May 5; 1855 May 13; 1855 Aug. 24; 1855 Dec. 15; 1856 Mar. 16.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Hunter Mine 1854 July 16
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. King Mountain Mine 1850 Mar. 23; 1855 Jan. 24; 1871 Nov. 1; 1873 Jan. 19; 1874 Mar. 21; 1876 Feb. 21; Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," p. 15).
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Lemon [?] Mine 1849 Feb. 18
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Long Creek Mine Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 9,15)
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. McCullock Gold Mine 1853 May 30; 1853 Oct. 30.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. McGinn Gold and Copper Mine 1849 Feb. 3; 1849 Feb. 10; 1853 Apr. 16; 1853 Apr. 19; 1853 Apr. 22; 1853 Oct. 30; 1853 Nov. 1; 1853 Nov. 3; 1854 Jan. 18; 1854 Feb. 5; 1854 Apr. 2; 1854 May 21; 1854 Dec. 3; 1854 Dec. 10; 1854 Dec. 22; 1855 Jan. 24; 1855 Feb. 11; 1855 Mar. 4; 1855 Apr. 2
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining [?]. Maxwell Mine 1849 Feb. 13; 1849 Mar. 10; 1850 Dec. 16; 1851 Oct. 5; 1851 Oct. 7; 1853 May 7; 1853 Aug. 15; 1856 Mar. 4; 1856 Nov. 18; 1856 Dec. 3; 1857 Mar. 21; Legal Papers: 1860 Aug. 4.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. O'Farrell Mine 1849 Feb. 10; 1853 Apr. 3; 1853 Apr. 5; 1853 Apr. 16; 1853 May 7; 1853 Aug. 21; Legal Papers: 1860 Aug. 4.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Oliver Mine 1849 Apr. 14; 1849 June 22; 1849 July 25; 1849 July 28; 1853 Apr. 9; 1854 Mar. 21.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Rudisill Hill Gold Mine 1854 Aug. 20; 1855 Aug. 17; 1856 May 4; 1856 Sept. 2; 1856 Dec. 21; 1857 Nov. 14; 1858 Mar. 31; 1858 Apr. 21; 1866 Mar. 28; Legal Papers: Undated.
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Saint Catherines Mills 1854 Mar. 11; 1854 Mar. 16; 1854 Mar. 18; 1854 Mar. 21; 1854 Mar. 22; 1854 Mar. 23; 1854 Mar. 29; 1854 Apr. 2; 1854 May 21; 1854 May 29; 1854 June 27; 1854 July 2; 1854 July 9; 1854 July 23; 1854 Aug. 20; 1854 Nov. 1; 1854; 1856 Mar. 31; 1857 Mar. 21; 185
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Tradywick [?] Mine 1853 Apr. 16
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Trotten Hill Gold Mine 1855 Aug. 17
North Carolina. Gold Mines and Mining. Watkins Mine 1853 Aug. 21
North Carolina. Greensboro. Gold Mines and Mining 1853 Oct. 30
North Carolina. High Shoals. Description and Travel Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina,")
North Carolina. High Shoals. Gold Mines and Mining Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 9-10, 13-15)
North Carolina. Iron Industry and Trade 1849 Nov. 26; 1867 Jan. 30; 1867 Feb. 4; 1868 Feb. 3; Printed Material: "Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp 12-13.
North Carolina. Iron Ores Printed Material: "Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 4-9
Labor and Laboring Classes. North Carolina 1856 May 31; 1856 July 24; 1856 Aug. 3.
North Carolina. Lawyers 1876 Apr. 3
North Carolina. Lead Mines and Mining. Silver Hill Mine 1856 Oct. 19
North Carolina. Limestone Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," p. 11)
North Carolina. Lincolnton. Description and Travel 1849 June 30
North Carolina. Mecklenburg County. Fairs 1857 Nov. 22; 1871 Nov. 1; 1871 Nov. 8.
North Carolina. McGinn. Mills and Millwork 1855 June 10; 1855 July 21; 1855 Aug. 1.
North Carolina. Mills and Millwork, 1848 Aug. 29; 1848 Oct. 26; 1848 Nov. 3; 1848 Nov. 8; 1848 Nov. 19; 1848 Nov. 22; 1848 Nov. 23; 1848 Nov. 24; 1848 Nov. 30; 1848 Dec. 7; 1848 Dec. 9; 1848 Dec. 10; 1848 Dec. 27; 1849 Jan.-Apr. (scattered); 1865 May 28; 1866 July 9.
North Carolina. Mills and Millwork. St. Catherine's Mills 1848 Nov.-1851 Oct. (scattered); 1852 Oct. 7; 1853 Mar.-1853 Sept. (scattered); 1860 July 18; 1866 Nov. 9; 1870 Feb. 13; 1870 Apr. 11; 1870 Apr. 20; 1871 May 24.
North Carolina. Mines and Mining, 1859; 1867 Mar. 28; 1872 June 17; 1874 Mar. 29.
North Carolina. Mines and Mining. Claremont Mine 1856 Feb. 4
North Carolina. Mines and Mining. Conrad Hill Mine 1853 Oct. 30
North Carolina. Mines and Mining. Harlan Mine 1853 Oct. 30
North Carolina. Mines and Mining. Long Creek Mine 1876 Apr. 16; 1876.
North Carolina. Nails and Spikes, 1866 Oct. 3; 1866 Dec. 6; 1866 Dec. 14; 1867 Jan. 10; 1867 Jan. 17; 1867 Jan. 30; 1867 Mar. 4; 1867 Mar. 14; 1867 Mar. 28; 1867 May 28; 1867 Sept. 11; 1867 Sept. 25; 1867 Oct. 24.
North Carolina. Negro Blacksmiths, 1849 Aug. 18
North Carolina. Negro Miners, 1854[?] Jan. 1; 1857 Nov. 29; 1876 Apr. [?].
North Carolina. Negroes 1875 Aug. 29; 1876 Jan. 8.
North Carolina. Political Parties. Democratic 1858 Apr. 15
North Carolina. Political Parties. Republican 1876 Mar. 26
North Carolina. Politics and Government 1874 July 27
North Carolina. Population 1867 Jan. 30
North Carolina. Pyrites Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," p. 14
North Carolina. Railroads 1857 Jan. 3; 1859 Feb. 27; 1860 Jan. 2; 1860 Nov. 27; 1865 May 20; 1865 May 28; 1865 June 20; 1866 Dec. 14; 1872 Nov. 15; 1876 Apr. 8; Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 2, 12, 14).
North Carolina. Reconstruction, 1865 May 20; 1865 May 28; 1865 June 20; 1866 Mar. 28; 1866 Dec. 14; 1868 Feb. 3; 1870 Aug. 3.
North Carolina. Roads 1859 Feb. 27; 1861 Feb. 6.
North Carolina. Secession 1860 Nov. 23; 1861 Feb. 6.
North Carolina. Silver Mines and Mining. Silver Hill Mine 1856 Oct. 19
North Carolina. Skating 1855 Jan. 17; 1856 Jan. 13; 1856 Jan. 14.
North Carolina. Slave Sales and Purchases 1849 Aug. 18
North Carolina. Slaves. Hiring of, 1850 Jan. 1; 1850 Jan. 14; 1850 Jan. 31; 1850 Feb. 8; 1850 June 20; 1853 Nov. 1; 1856 Aug. 26; 1857 Jan. 3.
North Carolina. Social Conditions, 1848 Dec. 30
North Carolina. Sulpher Mines and Mining 1867 Mar. 5
North Carolina. Charlotte. Tobacco Manufacture and Trade 1876 Feb. 21
North Carolina. Turpentine Industry and Trade 1853 Mar. 31
North Carolina. Wages 1849 Jan. 30; 1849 Feb. 6; 1849 Mar. 21; 1849 Apr. 4; 1849 June 12; 1854 Jan. 10; 1854 Mar. 5.
North Carolina. Wages. Agricultural, 1857 Nov. 22
North Carolina. Wages. Blacksmiths 1854 Jan. 10; 1854 Feb. 1; 1854 Dec. 31; 1857 Jan. 3.
North Carolina. Wages. Carpenters, 1854 Jan. 18; 1854 Jan. 28.